<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<book title="Jumpstart Your Experience" coverPhoto="jumpstart_cover.jpg">
  <chapter id="1" title="Customer Centric Marketing: An Introduction" pageCount="20">
    <page pageNumber="1">
      <text title="The need for customer-centric marketing" id="{25196275-0E38-476D-A327-3038B917B5D5}">
        Today, marketing managers recognize that customer knowledge has become a promising
        means of building comparative advantages, defending competition, and growing
        revenue (Sawhney, et al. 2004).
        Companies have
        changed their thinking from being product centric and holding a “one-size fits
        all” monologue with themselves, to being customer-centric and having a
        “one-to-one” dialogue with each customer. Instead of having no differentiation
        or customization, companies must begin to treat customers in a highly differentiated
        and customized fashion.
      </text>
      <text title=" " id="{2F03672D-BFA1-4252-8917-94833D0F5485}">
        Customers
        have come to represent firm assets, and firms' marketing focus has shifted from
        being "product-centric" or "campaign-centric" to
        "customer-centric". The traditional process of mass marketing is being
        challenged by a new <i>interactive </i>marketing approach (Blattberg and
        Deighton 1991; Haeckel 1998) or by one-to-one marketing that aims to profit
        from relationship building (Peppers et al. 1999; Wind and Rangaswamy 2001; Rust
        et al. 2004). This trend has been fueled by the rapid development of the
        Internet and digital technology, which tremendously increase the amount of
        detailed customer information available and create highly interactive
        environments for marketing communications (Shugan 2004).
      </text>
    </page>

    <page pageNumber="2">
      <img src="image001.png" alt="Image001" id="{C7AC5679-FE04-4C76-A9A8-453FEF4ED673}">Figure 1</img>

      <text title="What is customer-centric marketing?" id="{4F577009-8834-45CD-8E13-27AB86333783}">
        Customer-centric marketing means putting
        the customer at the center of your marketing strategy.  It emphasizes
        understanding and satisfying the needs, wants, and resources of individual consumers
        and customers rather than those of mass markets or market segments. In
        customer-centric marketing, marketers assess each customer individually and make
        a determination of whether to serve that customer directly or via a third
        party. Also, customer-centric marketing determines whether to create an
        offering that customizes  the product
        and/or some other elements of the marketing mix or standardize the offering
        (See Figure 1).
      </text>

      <text title=" " id="{09A1FEEE-CD1D-4C99-9621-EC9BCC472C5F}">
        Ideally, the
        firm should follow the development of each individual customer and develop
        integrated multi-segment, multi-stage, and multi-channel marketing mix
        decisions in order to maximize the total customer lifetime profit. 
      </text>

    </page>

    <page pageNumber="3">
      <text title=" " id="{E7A125A0-435A-409C-9F35-CEDF8E828DD2}">
        It is all about introducing the right marketing mix offering to the
        right customer at the right
        time through the right channel to satisfy the customer’s evolving demands in
        order to maximize customer life time value.
        The objective of customer-centric
        marketing is to maximize both efficiency and effectiveness simultaneously at a
        customer level in order to maximize the customer’s life-time profit
        contribution.
      </text>

      <text title=" " id="{F40BB58B-CF9E-4A98-AF56-31F17CE4A9C9}">
        Customer-centric
        marketing requires a company to track and understand needs, wants, and
        resources of individual consumers, and make an integrated decision on whether,
        when, what, and how to serve each individual consumer. The firm’s actions are
        guided by analysis that seeks to maximize the “effectiveness and efficiency” of
        its marketing actions. Efficiency entails cost-benefit analysis and seeks to
        maximize the output-to-input ratio. Effectiveness entails the enhancement of
        customer loyalty and "share of wallet" during their lifetime. The objective is
        to maximize each individual consumer’s long-term profit contribution.
      </text>
      <text title="Why customer-centric marketing?" id="{279CEDFB-9678-4F53-BDFF-619503C8662B}">
        The answer to the question "why should we switch to a customer-centric marketing approach?" is
        an economic one: Because it will increase profits. This will happen for
        some of the following reasons.
      </text>
    </page>

    <page pageNumber="4">
      <text title=" " id="{7D77914E-25CB-4485-B76E-D6762F5C611A}">
        First, consumer resistance to intrusive marketing is increasing:
        <ul>
          <li>68% of consumers agree there are too many ads today</li>
          <li>63% of US households wish they got less direct mail</li>
          <li>66% of emails received are unwanted</li>
        </ul>
        Second, consumers are actively taking control away from marketers:
        <ul>
          <li>75% of consumers have or intend to sign up for Do-Not-Call lists</li>
          <li>74% have or intend to install pop-up and Spam blockers</li>
        </ul>
        Third, more effectiveness can be achieved:
        <ul>
          <li>Customer-focused (as opposed to promotional and product-focused) communications will increase customer loyalty 
              and, as a result, customers will buy more over a longer period of time</li>
        </ul>
        Fourth, more efficiency can be achieved: 
        <ul>
          <li>Marketing investment will be better aligned with customer profit potential so marketing will become more cost-efficient (There will be less wasted marketing dollars on low-potential customers)</li>
          <li>There is also a potential for a huge reduction in segment-targeted direct mail with its associated environmental benefits.</li>
        </ul>
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="5">
      <text title=" " id="{B0617382-BB19-4bf6-B92E-50EC101107AD}">
      Customer-centric marketing is more than all of the above – it has the potential to redefine the way marketing
      is currently practiced to focus on the needs of the consumer, not the marketer. Instead of interruption marketing,
      it urges firms to practice permission marketing.
      </text>
      <img src="image002.png" alt="Image002" id="{9ACF46B2-5DF6-434e-9B1C-113561705917}">Figure 2</img>
      <text title="How Are Customer-Centric Marketing Decisions Made Differently?" id="{4A41C07A-9447-48f0-B089-73093FB31221}">
      Conceptually, the core idea behind customer-centric marketing is to identify customer heterogeneity (e.g., demand, taste, cost to serve, sensitivity to firm's decision variables)
      and customize marketing interventions that are relevant to the status and preferences of each customer. The goal is to acquire, nurture, and retain customers to 
      maximize customer lifetime contribution to the company's profit, 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="6">
      <text title=" " id="{026D5CB7-5857-4ff5-871A-E7530540D05A}">
      while controlling costs. Intuitively, three components characterize customer-centric marketing: 
      Customer knowledge, which identifies customers, follows their evolving demand, and/or tracks changes in customer preference (Rossi et al. 1996); foresight 
      about customers' future reaction to current marketing interventions and hence their long-term profit contributions (Berger et al. 2002); and a sequence of 
      customized and inter-temporally related marketing treatments (Anderson 2006).
      <br/>
      Accordingly, implementing customer-centric marketing takes two iterative steps:
      <ol>
        <li>The firm continuously learns about each individual customer by analyzing results from the recent interactions, and then</li>
        <li>it adapts its decisions according to its recent updated knowledge about each customer.</li>
      </ol>
      The first step involves learning; the firm analyzes customer information on the basis of revealed customer reactions to the firm's most recent actions. The 
      second step pertains to acting on information; the firm incorporates the updated knowledge into its marketing decisions, such as price, promotion, advertising, 
      and product design.  During this iterative process, updated knowledge continuously adjusts firm decisions, and the resulting customer reactions again inform 
      the learning process. Thus, learning and decision making are inter-dependent. We term this increasingly observed business practice of continuous learning and 
      acting on customer information for the purpose of maximizing long-term profit
      </text>
    </page>

    <page pageNumber="7">
      <text title=" " id="{F8FABE63-A2A4-4fa7-A6C5-805F3BD4196E}">
       ``customer information management" (CIM), and this require firms to 
      <ul>
        <li>Track and learn consumer development</li>
        <li>Foresee future profit potential</li>
        <li>Offer consumers one-on-one marketing treatment</li>
      </ul>
      </text>
      <text title="The Three Components of Customer-Centric Marketing Decisions" id="{BC54386D-86C3-4771-B81B-BACF0617BF34}">
      Customer-centric marketing decision making requires three important components:(i) learning about customer, (ii) a forward-looking component into customer’s 
      life time value, and (iii) optimally trading off short-term costs and long-term profit.
      <br></br>
      First, the firm needs to track the development of each customer (<strong><em>learning</em></strong>).  As demonstrated by Kamakura, Ramaswami and Srivastava (1991) and Li, 
      Sun and Wilcox (2005), customers’ demand for various products seems to be governed by a latent and evolving demand state or maturity, which develops 
      over time with changes in life-stage, accumulation of consumption experience, available financial resources, and learning about particular products. 
      The evolving, but latent, demand maturity represents an individual customer’s readiness for a particular product at a certain time. 
      It is an important predictor for products that are most likely to be purchased at a certain time by a particular customer
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="8">
      <text title=" " id="{093B5BDA-A5A0-4c0f-B693-CF728893F04C}">
       and likely to lead to a better 
      understanding of the timing on marketing opportunities.
      <br></br>
      Second, the firm needs to expect future profit potential (<strong><em>forward-looking</em></strong>). Marketing is an important part of long-term customer relationship 
      management with the goal of maximizing total profit throughout the entire customer lifecycle (Sun, Li and Zhou 2006). This requires the company 
      to be able to follow the evolution of customer needs, predict their future profit potential and be willing to forgo short-term profit in order 
      to maximize long-term profit. Current practice calculates net present value of customers’ future profits and treats this as another segmentation 
      variable to guide targeting strategies for a scheduled campaign. Although future profit is taken into account, this net present value approach is still 
      used only as an ad hoc segmentation strategy. This is different from a forward-looking approach of holistically making multi-state and multi-channel 
      marketing campaign decisions over a period of time, so future consequences affect the derived optimal cross-selling decisions.
      <br></br>
      Third, the firm needs to make optimal decisions (<strong><em>optimization</em></strong>). To make the optimal choice among alternative marketing campaign strategies 
      regarding who, when, what and how decisions, the company needs to integrate its knowledge on evolution of household demand maturity and their heterogeneity, 
      predict the dynamic consequences of its marketing 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="9">
      <text title=" " id="{08AA21CE-5307-439a-8602-3FBA2AC7AEBD}">
      solicitations, take into account the cost of acquisition and household’s long-term profit contribution, 
      and make optimal trade-off between short-term solicitation cost and long-term financial payoff in order to maximize “lifetime” profit of customers. This is 
      a complicated problem that is not easily handled by traditional household models, regression or segmentation approaches from data-mining. Given the nature of 
      the problem, the most parsimonious way to obtain the answer is to treat marketing decisions as solutions to a stochastic optimization problem under demand 
      uncertainty.  The demand uncertainty comes from households’ future demand in response to marketing solicitations. 
      </text>
      <text title="The Four Salient Features of Customer-Centric Marketing Decisions" id="{05407896-2975-4e2c-8664-AF83B15616C7}">
      Customer-centric marketing decisions have four features.
      <br></br>
      First, the decision should be <strong><em>customized</em></strong> because adaptive learning enables the firm to improve its knowledge about each individual customer and make marketing offers 
      according to its best knowledge about that customer’s preferences. Recognizing the evolving needs of each customer, our solution recommends the most 
      appropriate marketing offers to meet the evolving needs of a customer. With the understanding of customer preference for different campaign channels, 
      our solutions also allow us to adopt the most effective campaign vehicle, tailored to an individual’s preference. For example, since we recognize the educational 
      role of 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="10">
      <text title=" " id="{399C06F3-2D8B-4562-BC54-5084EABAB7E3}">
      cross-selling campaigns by treating them as an integrated multi-stage process instead of a promotion that triggers immediate purchase, our framework 
      differentiates short-term unprofitable customers and allows the company to sacrifice short-term profits for greater long-term profits (such as in the case of customers 
      who are students with potential to turn profitable).
      <br></br>
      Second, it should be <strong><em>dynamic</em></strong> because the decisions on when and which product to send solicitation is made in accordance with the development of household demand 
      maturity state. Continuing the example of a student customer of a bank, a graduation event could trigger an offer for automobile or home loans.
      <br></br>
      Third, it should be <strong><em>proactive</em></strong> because the firm takes into account the trade-off between short-term service costs and the long-term consequences of alienating customers, 
      which implies that it can sacrifice short-term profits by offering customers his preferred offer to prevent defection and improve long-term profits. Offering the student 
      customer with a typical profile a credit card account early in her career could potentially earn her loyalty over a long profitable career.
      <br></br>
      Fourth, our proposed allocation decisions are <strong><em>experimental</em></strong>, in the sense that the forward-looking firm may sub-optimally assign a customer to a 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="11">
      <text title=" " id="{3D90ADD6-F707-4855-8122-BE0435BC1C3F}">
      center to collect more information and learn about his or her type faster. The experimental property resulting from dynamics decision making under uncertainty has been 
      discussed by Erdem and Keane (1996) in the context of consumer purchases of frequently purchased packaged goods. In our running example, testing whether a student customer 
      is a sound candidate for an eventual home loan can be accomplished by offering her a small educational loan during her educational tenure and monitoring her payment 
      behavior.
      </text>
      <text title="What fuels customer-centric marketing?" id="{2181E119-3950-434d-9952-C333E6EE2784}">
      Given the central role of individualization in moving toward customer-centricity, companies from all types of industries, ranging from manufacturing to online retailing, 
      are exploring innovative ways to accumulate and understand customer information. Sophisticated analytical tools such as data warehousing and data mining technologies offer 
      promising means of gaining detailed knowledge about each customer. The recent move towards big data and cloud computing that make the collection, storage and access of such 
      vast interaction information very easy has also fueled the trend towards customer-centricity.
      <br></br>
      Realizing that understanding customers provides only a foundation but that acting on information represents the ultimate step towards customer-centric marketing, 
      firms also seek analytical marketing solutions that 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="12">
      <text title=" " id="{87A5CA02-E95E-4142-B7F1-456F55CF78B1}">
      enable them customize their marketing decisions, such as promotion, advertising, and product design, according 
      to their most updated customer information. These data mining and analytical tools let them (instantly) retrieve the most recent customer information, continuously 
      learn about the preferences of individual customers, respond directly to customer requests, and provide customers with highly customized intervention 
      decisions (Weiner 2001). A report by the independent market analyst Data Monitor forecasts global enterprise investments in data mining and analytical marketing tools 
      will grow from an estimated $2.3 billion in 2005 to more than 3 billion in 2009. IDC recently published a report on the market for Big Data technology and services, 
      which it estimates will grow at an annual rate of 40% to reach almost $17 billion by 2015. Another report by Forrester Research forecasts that U.S. interactive marketing 
      spending will reach $76.6 billion by 2016, equal to TV spending in 2012 and comprising 35% of all advertising, up from 19% of all spending in 2012.
      <br></br>
      As a concrete example, the recommendation system adopted by Amazon.com allows the online retailer to analyze customer preferences using their recent purchase 
      histories and (automatically) recommends other products for the purpose of improving customers' shopping experiences and future cross-sell opportunities. 
      Credit card companies use real-time data mining to screen credit applicants, predict credit fraud, and customize their offers and alerts. Ameritrade develops 
      long-term, 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="13">
      <text title=" " id="{F1B0A869-94CD-4c82-BACF-3CE9BF690149}">
      one-to-one marketing communication plans to improve the lifetime value of each customer by considering the benefits of customer acquisition over a 
      long period of time.
      <br></br>
      In the retail sector, retailers should base their marketing programs on three basic tenets:
      <ul>
        <li>Acquire new customers that have the best potential to become long-term customers. Go for quality, not quantity in the customer acquisition process.</li>
        <li>Determine as early in the relationship as possible which new customers have the greatest potential to become high-value, long-term customers — and focus marketing 
        spending on them rather than on low-potential customers.</li>
        <li>Reward existing high-value, loyal customers with special treatment in order to retain a higher percentage of them, since they are the customers keeping you in 
        business.</li>
      </ul>
      </text>
      <text title="Leveraging the Computing Advantage" id="{8DD21FB8-D101-4b2f-B4BC-38DB660FFEF4}">
      In response to the growing demand for integrated data mining and analytical decision tools, new software applications, under the names of customer relationship 
      management (CRM) or Web analytics (WA), have made significant inroads among commercial firms, which allows the 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="14">
      <text title=" " id="{A6E55A52-2237-4ac5-8732-00DCB515CC74}">
      adopters to automate their data mining and decision making processes. For instance, the On-Demand Customer Relationship Management by Saleforce.com claims that the 
      software provides ``point-and-click customization that fits the way you sell" and that ``real-time analytics empower your business to make better decisions." Microsoft 
      Dynamics CRM 3.0 Professional Datasheet claims that it ``is a complete customer relationship management solution that provides all of the tools and capabilities needed 
      to create and easily maintain a clear picture of customers from first contact through purchase and post-sales."
      <br></br>
      Recent technological developments have opened massive opportunities to advance and automate CRM decisions. They transform the CRM system from a data collection and 
      storage technology into one that promotes service excellence and identify revenue growth opportunities (Weiner 2001). Ideal CRM interventions should be customer-centric 
      by following the development of each individual customer and making multi-segment, multi-stage, and multi-channel CRM interventions with the goal of maximizing the 
      total customer profit. However, most recent CRM practices are still conveniently campaign-centric, in which the focus is on selecting the most profitable customers for 
      a scheduled CRM intervention.
      <br></br>
       “Extraordinary increases in computational speed allow sellers to use more sophisticated tools to quickly analyze traditional databases and to continuously improve 
       targeting strategies” (Shugan 2003). 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="15">
      <text title=" " id="{12293FFF-A2C4-4e86-99E3-BD5A503D9F5E}">
      The fast development of on-line and direct marketing industries creates enormous opportunity for adaptive learning and proactive 
      marketing decision making.  This calls for substantial research to develop statistical algorithms to measure customer insights and develop optimization routines as 
      decision-support systems to automate the implementations of marketing decisions to better manage customer relationships. For companies with difficulties automating 
      the implementation of CRM decisions, the statistical properties derived from the proposed framework provide descriptive guidance for managers to adjust their CRM 
      decisions.
      </text>
      <text title="Reconciling two viewpoints" id="{77009001-AB6A-4b1e-BC25-F06AF69922F9}">
      The rapid growth of demand for and supply of sophisticated data mining and analytical decision tools calls for research to understand the value of learning and how 
      learning interacts with a firm's day-to-day marketing strategies. Unfortunately, the inter-related issues of data mining customer information and the firm’s 
      analytical decision making followed separate streams in the academic literature. On the one hand, marketing researchers develop statistical approaches to 
      identify consumer heterogeneity (e.g., Kamakura and Russell 1989; Rossi et al. 1996) without explicitly deriving firm decisions.  This line of research results 
      in a snap shot segmentation of customers and score rankings of consumers based on relevant variables. These segmentation methods are useful tools for campaign-centric 
      marketing, which maximizes the return of investment of each campaign event by treating them independently over time. On the  
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="16">
      <text title=" " id="{D2EC683D-10F0-4261-8D1F-E2AD2998FA4A}">
      other hand, financial and information 
      economists have explicitly treated firms as decision makers that optimally act on information. However, by focusing on information at the aggregate demand or product level, 
      this stream of literature ignores firms' incomplete information about individual consumers. The approach we propose reconciles these multiple points of view: We 
      advocate using the economist’s point of view in the firm’s decision making process but take into account all the available customer information data from marketing 
      analytics, and propose constructing a long-term model that tracks the firm’s interaction with the customers effectively and efficiently.
      </text>
      <text title="Some Pioneers" id="{8FE6F0D4-6BCB-4b9e-A48D-AA36F6F4F97E}">
      </text>
      <img src="Harrahs.png" alt="Harrahs" id="{25C7A3C3-C98E-4972-A108-422CF6403F99}"></img>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="17">
      <text title="Harrah’s Entertainment banks on delivering what its customers want (Millstein 2007)" id="{F7C583CD-693F-423d-976E-16AA1647FC2D}">
      For example, Harrah’s knows exactly where its profits come from --- and that extends far beyond the gaming tables. It is based on precise details of what its 
      customers want and catering to them so they keep coming back. Harrah’s has information on over 30 million people in the United States. It knows what its customers 
      play, when they gamble and how much money they spend at spas or other non-gambling activities such as shopping. “Some customers will spend $1,000 a night with us 
      and not gamble at all,” said the Steve Pinchuk, corporate VP of revenue management for Harrah’s Entertainment. Making money and catering to customers is a particularly 
      complex system driven by advanced customer loyalty and revenue-management programs. The goal, above all else, is to avoid “promiscuous” behavior by gamers—meaning 
      keeping Harrah’s customers from “straying” into another owner’s casino where a bond could be formed.
      <br></br>
      The casino sends targeted offers to its frequent guests offering discounts on special tickets that they know will match particular desires. It does the same for its 
      guests in the casino and once they return home. Harrah’s Entertainment represents an almost a scientific brainstorming center for analyzing customer spending and 
      shopping behavior, and then treating each person in the way that ensures the best experience well beyond the notion of winning money.
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="18">
      <img src="Bloomingdales.png" alt="Bloomingdales" id="{B357C5FE-FC4E-4258-9DEC-5E9B36E81C97}"></img>
      <text title="Integration drives greater value: Bloomingdale’s" id="{ECBE747A-FE3C-4de1-BCF9-C491240C0E30}">
      Bloomingdale’s, the upscale department store division of Federated Department Stores, exemplifies a retailer with a foundational level of customer information integration 
      that is used to deliver greater value to its customers. First, it integrates customer transactional data with other long-term information about its customers to better 
      understand customers’ shopping patterns. By analyzing these spending patterns of when they shop and what they buy, Bloomingdale’s is able to anticipate customers’ needs 
      and dynamically adjust its merchandising and marketing strategies. Second, the company uses this integrated information to drive its customer relationship management 
      program. Using internal systems, Bloomingdale’s can access two-year’s worth of purchasing data to create and deliver targeted offers to points of sale. Messages are sent 
      to store employees to read to specific customers they are serving. The messages 
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="19">
      <text title=" " id="{998B2716-D9BC-4162-8C19-5D8AEB4C4306}">
      inform shoppers about special benefits they have qualified for based on their purchases, such 
      as an invitation to a party or a private sales event. Customers enjoy the personalized service and have responded favorably to the program.
      <br></br>
      In this book, we discuss the two-step procedure (“adaptive” learning and “proactive” marketing decisions) and three-components for customer-centric marketing. We 
      formulate marketing interventions as solutions to a stochastic dynamic programming problem under demand uncertainty in which the company needs to learn about the 
      evolution of customer demand, the dynamic effect of its marketing interventions, the heterogeneity of customer preferences, the cost of interventions, and the 
      long-term payoff, with the goal of maximizing the “long-term” profit of each customer. We also use four examples to demonstrate the input, output, and benefit 
      of “adaptive” learning and “proactive” marketing.  Our proposed solution meets the recent demand of companies seeking real-time solutions for integrating database 
      and marketing decisions that are empowered by the advancement of information technology.
      </text>
    </page>
    <page pageNumber="20">
    </page>
  </chapter>
</book>