<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<book title="Jumpstart Your Experience" coverPhoto="jumpstart_cover.jpg">
  <chapter id="1" title="Customer Centric Marketing: An Introduction" pageCount="4">
    <page pageNumber="1">
      <text title="The need for customer-centric marketing" id="{25196275-0E38-476D-A327-3038B917B5D5}">
        Today, marketing managers recognize that customer knowledge has become a promising
        means of building comparative advantages, defending competition, and growing
        revenue (Sawhney, et al. 2004).
        Companies have
        changed their thinking from being product centric and holding a “one-size fits
        all” monologue with themselves, to being customer-centric and having a
        “one-to-one” dialogue with each customer. Instead of having no differentiation
        or customization, companies must begin to treat customers in a highly differentiated
        and customized fashion.
      </text>
      <text title=" " id="{2F03672D-BFA1-4252-8917-94833D0F5485}">
        Customers
        have come to represent firm assets, and firms' marketing focus has shifted from
        being "product-centric" or "campaign-centric" to
        "customer-centric". The traditional process of mass marketing is being
        challenged by a new <i>interactive </i>marketing approach (Blattberg and
        Deighton 1991; Haeckel 1998) or by one-to-one marketing that aims to profit
        from relationship building (Peppers et al. 1999; Wind and Rangaswamy 2001; Rust
        et al. 2004). This trend has been fueled by the rapid development of the
        Internet and digital technology, which tremendously increase the amount of
        detailed customer information available and create highly interactive
        environments for marketing communications (Shugan 2004).
      </text>
    </page>

    <page pageNumber="2">
      <img src="image001.png" alt="Image001" 
           id="{C7AC5679-FE04-4C76-A9A8-453FEF4ED673}">
        Figure 1
      </img>

      <text title="What is customer-centric marketing?" id="{4F577009-8834-45CD-8E13-27AB86333783}">
        Customer-centric marketing means putting
        the customer at the center of your marketing strategy.  It emphasizes
        understanding and satisfying the needs, wants, and resources of individual consumers
        and customers rather than those of mass markets or market segments. In
        customer-centric marketing, marketers assess each customer individually and make
        a determination of whether to serve that customer directly or via a third
        party. Also, customer-centric marketing determines whether to create an
        offering that customizes  the product
        and/or some other elements of the marketing mix or standardize the offering
        (See Figure 1).
      </text>

      <text title=" " id="{09A1FEEE-CD1D-4C99-9621-EC9BCC472C5F}">
        Ideally, the
        firm should follow the development of each individual customer and develop
        integrated multi-segment, multi-stage, and multi-channel marketing mix
        decisions in order to maximize the total customer lifetime profit. 
      </text>

    </page>

    <page pageNumber="3">
      <text title=" " id="{E7A125A0-435A-409C-9F35-CEDF8E828DD2}">
        It is all about introducing the right marketing mix offering to the
        right customer at the right
        time through the right channel to satisfy the customer’s evolving demands in
        order to maximize customer life time value.
        The objective of customer-centric
        marketing is to maximize both efficiency and effectiveness simultaneously at a
        customer level in order to maximize the customer’s life-time profit
        contribution.
      </text>

      <text title=" " id="{F40BB58B-CF9E-4A98-AF56-31F17CE4A9C9}">
        Customer-centric
        marketing requires a company to track and understand needs, wants, and
        resources of individual consumers, and make an integrated decision on whether,
        when, what, and how to serve each individual consumer. The firm’s actions are
        guided by analysis that seeks to maximize the “effectiveness and efficiency” of
        its marketing actions. Efficiency entails cost-benefit analysis and seeks to
        maximize the output-to-input ratio. Effectiveness entails the enhancement of
        customer loyalty and "share of wallet" during their lifetime. The objective is
        to maximize each individual consumer’s long-term profit contribution.
      </text>
    </page>

    <page pageNumber="4">
      <text title="Why customer-centric marketing?" id="{279CEDFB-9678-4F53-BDFF-619503C8662B}">
        The answer to the question "why should we switch to a customer-centric marketing approach?" is
        an economic one: Because it will increase profits. This will happen for
        some of the following reasons.
      </text>

      <text title=" " id="{7D77914E-25CB-4485-B76E-D6762F5C611A}">
        First, consumer resistance to intrusive marketing is increasing:
        <li>
          <ul>68% of consumers agree there are too many ads today</ul>
        </li>
      </text>
    </page>
  </chapter>
</book>

